Friend
I understand. I can't be your boyfriend, but I can pretend to be one.
わかった
彼氏にはなれないが、振りはしてあげられる
Thank you. I'll try my best to make you love me.
ありがとう…
好きになってもらえれるよう、頑張る…
I'll show her L's face and find out his name, then I'll erase him along with his investigation team.
こいつに L の顔を見せ、
L の名前を知り、捜査本部もろとも消す…
Killing her can wait till after...
こいつを殺すのはその後だ
She's the one person that knows Kira's true identity.
そうとも、こいつはキラの正体を知ってしまった唯一の人間
I can't leave her alive for too long.
長く生かしておくわけにはいかない
"Pretend to be", huh?
彼氏の振りかぁ
I guess that'll do for now.
最初はそれでもいいや
Anyway, let's get to the point: will you show Misa your Shinigami?
じゃあ早速だけど、あなたの死神も海砂に見せて
I guess I'll have to if I want her to trust me.
信用させるのに必要か…
あぁ、わかった
Okay... turn around for me.
後ろ向いてくれるか
Okay!
はい
You can turn back now.
こっち向いていいよ
Okay!
はい
Heya!
どうも
Wow! Even though you're a Shinigami, you and Rem are completely different types!
へぇ～死神といってもレムとは全然違うタイプね
I've heard about you, if only by name, Ryuk!
名前だけは聞いてるよリューク
よろしくね
Nice to meet you!
はい、よろしく
Yes, nice to meet you too.
Oh yeah! Light! Do you know how Shinigami die?
そうそうライト知ってる？
死神が死ぬ方法
You're already using Light, my first name?
もう「ライト」って呼び捨てか
Well, can I call you "Knight" instead of "Light", then?
じゃあ「ライト」じゃなくて「ナイト」って呼んでいい？
海砂にとっては、白馬の騎士だもの
To Misa, you're like a knight on a white horse!
"Light" is fine.
…ライトでいいよ
You're not seriously going to check all the video footage from Aoyama on the 22nd all by yourself, are you?
その…
22日の青山関連のビデオ、一人で全部チェックする気ですか？
はい、
キラと第二のキラはここで接触した可能性が高いですから、
Yes. There is a real possibility that Kira and the second Kira made contact there.
I'd like to check all of these.
これは私が全部チェックしたい
Also, Yagami-san...
それと夜神さん
Ah, yes?
はい
模木さんに月君の行動を監視してもらってください
Have Mogi-san keep a close eye on Light-kun's movements.
Light's movements?
月の行動を？
If by any chance he really is Kira, the second Kira may try to approach him in some way.
万一月君がキラだった場合、
第二のキラが何らかの形で接触してくるかもしれません
I understand...
…わかった
I wonder when Ryuuzaki actually sleeps...
しかし竜崎って一体いつ寝てるんだ…
I caught him sleeping, just like that, in his chair once...
この前、あの姿勢のまま寝てるの見ましたよ
Huh?
No, really...
いや、本当に…
So, you're saying that if a Shinigami has feelings for a specific human, and kills another human, in order to prolong the lifespan of the one they have feelings for... they'll die?
じゃあ、特定の人間に好意を持ち、
その人間の寿命を延ばす目的で他の人間を殺すと、
So, you're saying that if a Shinigami has feelings for a specific human, and kills another human, in order to prolong the lifespan of the one they have feelings for... they'll die?
死神は死ぬってことか？
That's right.
そう
I can't imagine that any Shinigami would do something like that.
そんなことする死神がいると思えないけどな
Well, you'll certainly never do anything of the sort.
そうだな、
少なくともリュークは絶対になさそうだ
So, where have you been sending the video tapes to the TV station from?
ところで、今までテレビ局にテープを送ったのは、どこからだ？
Well... the first one was from Osaka, then from Tokyo, and the last one was from Nagano.
えっと…最初は大阪、次は東京、この前は長野
I tried to ensure that they couldn't pin down an exact location, so I used the shinkansen.
新幹線使って、場所の特定できないようにしたつもり
So, you still have tapes and envelopes with your friend's fingerprints, right?
で、まだ友達の指紋付きビデオテープや封筒は、残ってるんだな
Yeah.
うん
You better destroy everything you used to make those videos...
じゃあそれらビデオ作成に使ったものも全て処分すべき、
That is, after we send the final tape from yet another different location tomorrow.
だがそれは、明日また別の場所から、
局に最後のビデオを送ってからだ
What should it say?
その内容は…
"I have decided not to reveal myself to Kira. To the police, thank you very much for the warning.
「キラに名乗り出るのはやめます、
警察の皆さん、ご忠告ありがとうございました」
However, I will join Kira in purging the world of evil, and will gain their acceptance through aiding them.
「しかし、私はキラと共に世の中の悪を消していき、
キラに協力して認めてもらいます」
However, I will join Kira in purging the world of evil, and will gain their acceptance through aiding them.
「まずはキラがまだ裁けていない犯罪者を裁きます、
I will begin by passing judgment on all criminals that Kira has not judged already.
Then, I shall proceed by sharing these powers with people that I find worthy and would like to continue making this world a better place."
ちから
そして、
この能力を与えるに相応しい人間にはどんどん能力を分け
Then, I shall proceed by sharing these powers with people that I find worthy and would like to continue making this world a better place."
世の中を良くしていきたいと思います」
"Share these powers"?
ちから
「能力を分ける」？
It's simply a line to confuse the investigation.
捜査を混乱させる為の一文だ
ちから
既に二人も能力を持った者がいるんだ、
Since there are already two people who have this power, it's not inconceivable that there may be more.
何人になっても、不思議ではないし、
増えていくと考えれば焦りも生じる
If they believe that this figure could increase, they'll become more impatient.
Can you do this?
できるか？
Don't say "Can you do this?". Just tell me to do it!
「できるか？」じゃなくて、「やれ！」でいいよ
私はライトの言いなりになるから
I will do whatever you ask of me.
There's one more important thing that I've got to mention...
それともう一つ大事なこと…
Yes!
はい
もし警察に捕まったら、
If we get caught by the police... even if we get caught as suspects... we can't mention anything about each other or the notebooks.
容疑者として捕まったとしても、
絶対互いの事と、ノートの事は喋らない
If we get caught by the police... even if we get caught as suspects... we can't mention anything about each other or the notebooks.
ノートを押さえ検証しない限り、証拠はないんだから
Unless they have the notebooks, there is no proof.
Can you swear to this?
これを守れると誓えるか？
I swear!
誓いま～す
So, this concludes the boyfriend-girlfriend contract, right?
じゃあ、これで彼氏と彼女の契約は成立ね？
I guess so.
まぁそうなるか
Then, now for my stipulations:
ではこっちの条件
At minimum, there must be at least one date a week.
デートは最低でも週一回
She doesn't get it after all...
やっぱりわかってないこいつ…
無理だよ
That's not possible.
Why?!
っ！なんで？
It seems like you won't understand unless I spell it out for you.
言っておかないとわかってもらいそうにないな
L already suspects that I am Kira.
L は既に僕のことをキラではないかと疑っている
ええっ!?
Wow, this "L" is really impressive...
す…すごいのね L って
世の中じゃ、何もわかってない、
「 L は馬鹿」みたいに言われてるのに、
Most people believe that he knows nothing, or that he's an idiot, when in fact he's already...
本当はもうそこまで…
I won't say it's entirely thanks to that, but I've managed to get in direct contact with L.
しかしそのおかげとは言わないが、
僕も L と接触を持てる所まで来ている
I won't say it's entirely thanks to that, but I've managed to get in direct contact with L.
え、 L とキラが接触してるの？
L and Kira are in contact?! Both of you are amazing!
なんかすごいどっちも…ちょっとワクワクしちゃう
I'm getting a little excited...
L thinks that even if I am Kira, as long as he keeps his name hidden, he's safe.
L は、僕がキラであろうと、
名前を隠せば危険ではないと考え、
So, to investigate me further, he revealed himself to me as "L".
僕を直接探る為に、 L だと名乗り出た
But, the only proof he has, is that he has no other suspects.
しかし、
キラの可能性がある人間が他にいないから、その程度の確証だ
In fact, if I act naturally around him, I expect he'll trust me and we'll investigate together.
それどころか、こっちが上手く振る舞えば、
僕を信じ一緒に捜査するつもりだ
So, all you have to do is take Misa to L?
じゃあ、ライトが海砂を
L の所に連れて行ってくれればいいだけね？
It's not that easy.
そんな簡単にはいかないよ
It was hard enough for me to try and get close to him...
L に自分から近づくのは、僕だけでも難しかった
But more importantly, if someone suddenly starts to make contact with me, while at the same time,
それよりも、これから急に僕を近づく者が現れ、
Kira and the second Kira's attitudes towards society are changing, that person will be suspected of being the second Kira.
社会に対する、キラと第二のキラの態度に変化があれば、
その者が第二のキラである疑い、
僕がキラである疑いを、より深める事になりうる
The suspicions of me being Kira will then deepen.
We can't allow them to think that we've suddenly met and started to go out with each other.
君と僕が急接近し、
親密な関係になったとは思われるのはまずい
Do you understand what I'm saying?
言ってる意味わかるか
Sort of... is that why you're saying we won't be able to go out on dates?
なんとなくわかるけど…
だからデートできないってこと？
You can't see me because it'd make them suspicious?
疑いが深まるのが怖くて、会えないってこと？
No... it'd probably be better if you start thinking carefully about how you're going to see L's face without him discovering your existence.
いや、
まずは君の存在を L に知られずに、
君が L を見る策をじっくり考えるべき、
Yeah.
…うん
In order to get rid of L, I need you.
L を消すには君が必要だ
As much as possible, I'd like to meet you in person to pass on information...
君とはなるべく直接会って、連絡していきたい
Oh good!
よかった
...so, to ensure that our meetings remain unnoticed, I'll aim to go out with lots of different girls.
だから…
君に会うことが目立たないよう、
他の女の子とも沢山会うようにする
...so, to ensure that our meetings remain unnoticed, I'll aim to go out with lots of different girls.
Huh? What do you mean?
あ…なにそれ？
You'll be dating other girls?
他の女の子ともデートする？
That's what it'll come down to...
まぁそういうことに…
No way!!
そんなの嫌!!
If I see you doing that... I'll kill the girl.
そんなの見たら、その子殺しちゃうよ
Scary...
こえ
（『怖い』の口語的な言い方）
なぁ、海砂ちゃん
Hey, Misa-chan...
It's "chan" now, is it?
「ちゃん」かよ…
...this is not a game.
遊びじゃないんだ
二人で命懸けて、世の中を変えていくんだろ？
We're going to change the world, remember?
I know, but... Misa loves you more than the world...
そうだけど…海砂は、世の中よりライトが好き…
What are you talking about?
なに言ってるんだ
Your feelings for me should be those of a supporter.
君の僕への想いは、キラへの賛同者としてのはず
Besides, this is the first time you've ever spoken to me.
それにこうして話すのも初めてなのに…
You've never fallen in love at first sight?
一目惚れってした事ない？
No.
ないよ
海砂がキラに会いたかったのは、
確かに感謝と共感で、愛じゃなかったけど
It's true that I wanted to meet Kira out of gratitude and sympathy, as opposed to love.
But Light, from the first time I saw you, I...
ライトは一目見た時から、私…
What the hell is wrong with this woman?
なんなんだこの女は…
Popular as ever I see!
相変わらずモテモテだな
Well, if you love me, you can obey me, right?
じゃあ、僕を好きなら僕に従えるね
First, you said that you didn't mind if I used you, and that you'd do as I say, didn't you?
最初に「利用されるだけでもいい」、
さっきも「言いなりになる」って言ったよね？
But I can't forgive you if I see you with another girl!
でも、他の女の子とデートするのは許せない
These are two completely different issues!
それとこれとは別の話でしょ？
Right now, both Death Notes are in my hands.
ノートは今、二冊とも僕の手にある、
If you don't obey me, I'll kill you.
従えないなら僕は君を殺す…
そうはさせないよ
I won't let you do that... Yagami Light!
夜神月
If you try to kill this girl, I'll write your name in my own Death Note... and kill you.
もしこの娘を殺すような事をすれば、
私が私のノートにオマエの名前を書き、
If you try to kill this girl, I'll write your name in my own Death Note... and kill you.
お前を殺す
I can see this girl's lifespan.
この娘の寿命は私には見えている
If she dies before her time, I'll assume that you were responsible.
もしこの寿命の前に死んだら　お前が殺したとしか思わない
If you use the Death Note to kill me, in order to save her, wouldn't you die?
その子を助ける為にノートを使えば、
お前が死ぬんじゃなかったのか？
That's right. If you do that, Rem, you'll die!
そうよ、それじゃレムが死んじゃうじゃない
You're correct... but that's fine by me.
確かにそうだ
だが私はそれでも構わない
What's with this Shinigami... is she serious? Then from this point on...
なんなんだこの死神、本気か？
これじゃこの先…
Light?
月？
What is it, Mom?
なに？母さん
It's already 11:30. You shouldn't have a girl here so late...
もう11時半よ、女の子こんなに遅くまで…
Ah, that's true. We were busy talking.
ああ、そうだね
つい話し込んじゃって
Ah, that's true. We were busy talking.
Sorry, Mom!
すみません、お母さん
I apologize for intruding on you all till such a late hour.
夜遅くにお邪魔してすみませんでした
Light, I'll see you soon.
ライト、またね
ああ
Yeah.
Light, you should walk her to the station.
月、駅まで送ってあげなさい
Right now, walking around outside with her would be...
今この子と外を歩くのは…
あっ、大丈夫です
I'll be fine! Good night!
おやすみなさい
She's a cute girl.
可愛い子ね
Yup, yup. I wasn't too sure about her at first, but she's cute.
うんうん
最初はちょっとって思ってたけど、可愛いよね
She's my type!
私のタイプ
If I kill the girl, she'll kill me?
あの女を殺したら僕を殺すだと…
Does that mean I'll have to remain on Rem's good side until she dies?
あいつが死ぬまで、上手く付き合い続けなくてはならないのか
In addition, I'll have to protect her from getting caught by the police.
それどころか、警察に捕まらないように、
彼女の一生を見守ることも強いられる…
Thanks to you, Rem, Light truly is my "knight" now.
ナイト
レムのおかげで、ライトが本当に私の騎士になったね
Seems so.
そのようだね
But you know, you can't really kill him.
でも、本当に殺しちゃダメだよ
To kill a Shinigami, you have to make them use their Death Note to save someone they like.
死神を殺すには、
その死神が好意を持つ人間を助ける為に、
デスノートを使わせること…
Yet, I can't try to kill her first by manipulating someone via the Death Note to attack Misa.
レムを先に殺そうと思い、
僕がデスノートで誰かを操って海砂を襲わせる…
などはできない
If Misa gets intro trouble, I'll be the first person she'll suspect, and I'll be killed straight away.
海砂が危険な目に会えば、真っ先に僕が疑われ僕が殺される…
Currently, Rem's an even bigger threat than L.
こうなると、現時点で L よりも厄介な存在だ…
S-She's... doing something as high profile as this?!
こ、こいつ…
こんなに目立つことしてたのか…
S-She's... doing something as high profile as this?!
Amane Misa
Real name: Amane Misa
Hometown: Kyoto
D.O.B.: 1987 December 25th
Size: 152 tall, 76 bust, 51 waist, 75 hip
Blood type: AB
What will happen if they find out that I'm seeing someone like her?!
こうなると僕が会っているとわかったら、どうなるんだ？
Damn it! No matter how I look at it, she's just getting in the way.
くそ、どう考えても邪魔だ…
What can I do...
どうすれば…
Wait! More importantly, I need to think of a method of using Misa's eyes to kill L.
あいや…
それよりも、
海砂の目を利用し、 L を殺すことを考えるんだ
If only I could get rid of L...
L さえ消せば…
Onii-chan, good morning!
お兄ちゃんおはよう
Good morning.
おはよう
母さん、粧裕
Mom, Sayu, can you not mention Misa-chan to father?
海砂ちゃんの事は、父さんにはまだ黙っておいてくれないか
Okay, okay.
はいはい
Actually, it's not just father either. I'd like you not to mention this to anyone.
それと、
父さんだけじゃなく、誰にも言わないで欲しいんだ
Actually, it's not just father either. I'd like you not to mention this to anyone.
She's an up-and-coming model, so she's not really supposed to have a boyfriend or anything along those lines.
彼女、一応売れてきてるモデルだから、彼氏とかまずいんだ
Eh?! Really?! No wonder I thought she was cute!
えっ？そうなの～？どうりで可愛いと思った
さすがお兄ちゃんの彼女だ
Just what I'd expect from a girlfriend of yours.
I'll keep your secret... for 5,000 yen!
秘密にしとくよ～五千円でね
Moron.
バカ
Toudou University
今日…海砂から最後のメッセージが着く
The final message from Misa will arrive today.
It should be passed directly to the investigation, instead of going to the TV station.
しかしそのビデオはテレビ局には行かず、
捜査本部に回されるはずだ
I should stop by Investigative Headquarters and check L's reaction.
L の反応を見るために、今日は本部に行かなくては…
Yagami-kun.
夜神君
Yagami-kun... you said that you'd go out with me, didn't you?
これからお付き合いしてくださるって言いましたよね
Yeah, I did.
ああ、言った
そしてさっそく、こうした肩を並べて講義を受けています
And here we are, sitting together in lectures.
Yeah?
はい
Yet, you don't seem the least bit happy about it. You seem distracted.
なのに夜神君は少しも楽しそうじゃなく、ずっと上の空です
That's not true.
そんな事ないよ
I was just thinking that going out with "Miss Toudai" means that many people will be saying things about me.
ミス東大の呼び声高い高田さんと付き合うなんて、
周りから、色々言われるんだろうなって考えてたんだ
And truthfully, you are extremely beautiful, Takada-san.
事実、高田さん凄い美人だし
Please don't dwell upon such matters.
そんな事、考えないで下さい
私はミス何とかだとか、浮ついたものは嫌いです
I don't like fickle things such as "Miss Whatever".
Ah, you're right.
ああ、そうだね
Yet, she clearly didn't mind...
なんだこの女、まんざらでもないんだ
気にせず、僕たちのペースで行けばいいのかな、高田さん
Let's just go at our own pace without worrying about others, okay, Takada-san?
はい
Yes.
'Evening.
こんにちは
Light-kun, you've arrived at a good time.
月君
いいところに来てくれました
We've just received another video from the second Kira.
さっき第二のキラからメッセージビデオが届いたところです
Again? That was fast.
また？いやに早いな
Yes. They state that this is the final one.
はい
これが最後だと言ってます
Well, take a look.
ま、これを見てください
I have decided not to reveal myself to Kira.
キラに名乗り出るのはやめます
To the police, thank you very much for the warning.
警察の方、ご忠告ありがとうございました
しかし、私はキラに協力し、
However, I will join Kira in purging the world of evil, and will gain their acceptance through aiding them.
世の中の悪を裁いていき、キラに認めてもらいます
I will begin by passing judgment on all criminals that Kira has not judged already.
まずは、キラがまだ裁けていない犯罪者を裁きます
Then, I shall proceed by sharing these powers with people that I find worthy and would like to continue making this world a better place.
ちから
そして、この能力を与えるに相応しい人にも分け、
世界を変えていきたいと思います
私はこれを見て、
キラと第二のキラが繋がってしまったと感じました
Having watched this, I get the feeling that Kira and the second Kira have made contact.
Why do you feel that they've made contact?
何故繋がったと？
Didn't you feel it?
感じませんでしたか？
I assumed that you would get the same impression as I did.
月君なら私と同じ印象を受けると思っていたんですが
It's the fact that their insistence on meeting Kira has completely changed.
まず、あれだけキラに会う事に拘っていた態度が一変した事
Also, the fact that they now want to judge all the criminals Kira hasn't yet judged in order to be accepted by them.
そして今更キラに認めてもらう為に、
キラが裁けなかった犯罪者を裁くと言い出した事
Why hadn't they done that from the start?
これを今まで何故やらなかったか？
それはそこまで考えが及んでいなかったから
It's because they hadn't thought so far.
Presumably, they've managed to make contact with Kira, who told them to pass this judgment.
おそらくキラと繋がりを持ち、「裁け」と言われたんです
Kira has also asked to conceal this link between them.
そして…キラは「繋がりを持った事は隠せ」と命じた
In that case, Kira is acting without thinking too much then.
なるほど
それだとキラも…大して考えずに行動しているな
Yes.
はい
Has something happened to stop them from thinking so clearly?
考えが回らないほどの事情でもあったか、
Perhaps they're trying to confuse me by making the connection between them obvious.
繋がりを持った事をわざとわかるようにし、
こっちの動揺を誘ったかでしょうね
Realistically, this connection is a huge threat... but due to this, my suspicions towards Light-kun have lessened.
実際この繋がりは脅威です
しかし、これで月君がキラである疑いはまた減りました
…どういうことだ、竜崎
What do you mean by that, Ryuuzaki?!
If Light-kun was Kira, instead of sending a tape like this, I believe that he'd get the second Kira to make another threat forcing L... that is, me, to appear on TV.
月君がキラなら、第二のキラにはこんなビデオを送らせず、
もう一度 L 、私をテレビ出演させる脅迫をさせると思うんです
If Light-kun was Kira, instead of sending a tape like this, I believe that he'd get the second Kira to make another threat forcing L... that is, me, to appear on TV.
As long as we assumed they hadn't made contact yet, it would be the second Kira's responsibility...
繋がりができてないとしている以上、
第二のキラの責任になりますし
As long as we assumed they hadn't made contact yet, it would be the second Kira's responsibility...
そしてこう言わせればいい：
Then all he'd need to get them to say is:
"I stopped once when Kira told me to. But I no longer believe that that warning came from Kira. Kira should be pleased if L dies.
「一度はキラに言われて止めてたが、
その忠告はキラ本人のものとは思えなくなった」
"I stopped once when Kira told me to. But I no longer believe that that warning came from Kira. Kira should be pleased if L dies.
「 L が死ねばキラは喜ぶはず」
「止めるわけがない」…と
There's no way that they would try and stop me."
竜崎
Ryuuzaki...
Yes?
はい
If I truly were Kira... I wouldn't do that.
もし僕がキラだったら、そんな事はしないよ
Why?
何故？
If you genuinely are L, then I know your character.
竜崎が L であるのなら、僕は L の性格を知っている
No matter how you're threatened, there's no way that you'd actually appear on TV.
L はどんな脅迫をされようと、テレビに出たりはしない
You would never consider taking the fall for someone else.
人の身代わりになる気などさらさらない
Without a doubt, you'd have some sort of plan to get out of it.
何が逃れる手段を必ず考える
So you knew?
バレてましたか？
Light, even if it's purely theoretical, I want you to stop with this "If I were Kira" talk.
月、例え話でも、
「もし自分がキラなら」なんて話すのは止めろ
Ah, I'm sorry, father.
ああ、ごめん、父さん
But I want to express my thoughts clearly to Ryuuzaki.
でも竜崎には、自分の考えをちゃんと言いたいんだ
I want the case to end quickly, and then my name can be cleared.
この事件を早く解決する為にも、自分の疑いを晴らす為にも
Besides, the reason I can say "If I were Kira", is because I'm not Kira.
それに、「もし僕がキラなら」なんて話せるのは、
僕がキラじゃないからだよ
That's correct... Light-kun isn't Kira.
そうですね
月君はキラじゃない
Or should I say, it'd be a problem if he was, because... Light-kun is... the first friend I've ever had.
いや、月君がキラでは困ります
月君は…
Or should I say, it'd be a problem if he was, because... Light-kun is... the first friend I've ever had.
私の初めての友達ですから
You're a friend that I really get along with as well.
ああ、僕にとっても、竜崎は気が合う友達だ
Thanks.
どうも
It's lonely with you being absent from university.
大学、休学されて寂しいよ
また、テニスしたいね
I'd like to play tennis with you again at some point.
Yes, by all means.
はい、是非…
"Friend"?!
友達？友達か…
"Friend", huh? Well, good for you, Light.
よかったじゃないかライト
Ryuuzaki... he's easily managed to deduce the connection between Kira and the second Kira.
竜崎の奴、
あっさりとキラと第二のキラの繋がりに感づいている…
Looks like I'll need to get rid of my enemies as soon as possible.
やはりできるだけ早く消さなければ…
Oh, right...
ああそう
It'll be even more dangerous to meet Misa from now on.
これではますます、海砂に会うことは危険だ…
Light!
ライ～ト♡
どうしても二週間待てなくて
I couldn't wait an entire two weeks, so I was just on my way over to see you!
今ライトのうちに行こうとしてたところ
お…
This is the first time in my entire life that I seriously wanted to hit a girl...
女を殴りたいと本気で思ったのは、生まれて初めてだ
I just really wanted to see you...
ど…どうしても会いたくて…
Well, you'd better come to my house.
まぁ、うちに来いよ
うん！
また女の子…
A girl... again?
あ～海砂さんいらっしゃい
Misa-san, welcome!
I've seen a lot of magazines with you in them!
載ってる雑誌いっぱい見たよ
Welcome.
いらっしゃい
あは♪、お邪魔しま～す
Sorry for disturbing you.
Mom, can we have some tea?
母さん、お茶ね
Rem?
レム
Huh?
ん？
You're Misa's ally, right?
お前、海砂の味方してるよな
Yeah, well, I've seen this girl a number of times from the Shinigami world, and due to certain circumstances, I've got some feelings for her.
ああ、この子の事は死神界から何度か観ていたし、
ある事情があって少し情が移ってね
You've got feelings, despite being a Shinigami?
死神のくせに情か
「この子を殺そうとしたら、お前を殺す」
と言ったのが気に入らないようだな
Seems like you don't like the fact that I said, "If you kill this girl, I'll kill you".
So, does this mean that if Misa is happy, you're happy?
海砂が幸せになれば、レムも気分がいいってことか？
Yeah, that's how it works.
ああ、そういうことになる
I don't want to see her sad.
この子の不幸は見たくない
Misa really... likes me so much.
海砂はこんなに…
僕を好きでいる
Light?
ライト…
海砂…
Misa?
Yes?
はい
僕の幸せは、君の幸せになるか？
Is my happiness your happiness too?
Yes.
うん
レムに頼んでくれるか？
Can you ask Rem to kill L?
L を殺せって…
Rem wants you to be happy, yet if one of us is caught by L, that happiness will be threatened.
レムは君の幸せを願っているし、
おびや
どちらかが L に捕まりでもすれば、二人の幸せは脅かされる
Rem wants you to be happy, yet if one of us is caught by L, that happiness will be threatened.
Although Shinigami aren't supposed to tell humans other people's names, there's no rule that stipulates who Rem can and can't kill.
確かに死神は、人間に人の名前を教えてはいけないが、
レムが誰かを殺そうと、制約はないもんな
Yeah. If you kill L, I'll have even greater feelings for Misa, and I'd be thankful to you too, Rem.
ああ、もし L を殺してくれれば、
僕はよりに海砂を愛しく思うし、レムにも感謝する
Yeah. If you kill L, I'll have even greater feelings for Misa, and I'd be thankful to you too, Rem.
何より、二人が幸せになる
More importantly, we'd both be happy together.
Rem, I want to be loved by Light.
レム、ライトに愛されたい
Both of us will be happy... I'll be happy.
ライトも私も喜ぶし、
それが、私の幸せ
Okay...
いいだろう
Okay then, Yagami Light.
いいだろう、夜神月
私はオマエが嫌いだ、
I don't like you, so even if I end up prolonging your life, it won't kill me.
オマエの寿命を伸ばす結果になっても、私は死なない
I'll kill L. He means nothing to me.
L を殺してやるよ
L なんて私にとっては、どうでもいい人間だ
やった
Yay, Rem! Thank you!
レム、ありがとう
さすがレム
I knew you'd do it!
L is going to die... just like that?
L が死ぬ…
こんな簡単に…
To be continued
そうだ…
流河が L と名乗った以上…殺すべき
もうここは賭けだ
明日が L …
いや、少なくとも
竜崎．流河の命日だ！